VAYA CHOUCHOULI

Food Technologist



PROFILE

Experienced Food Technologist with a focus on Food contact materials (FCM). Over 15 years experience in Quality Control and Quality assurance departments, thorough knowledge of Food, Feed and FCM European, Greek and International Legislation and Laboratory skills in food microbiology. Highly organized person, persistent, restless spirit, always seeking for the best result.

LINKS

Linkedin

SKILLS

Quality Assurance /Quality Control

Legislation on Food, Feed, FCM (EU and International)

Food Microbiology Laboratory skills

Organizational, Persistant, Thorough, Communicational, Team working

MS Office Tools (Word, Excel, Power point)

LANGUAGES

Greek		
English		
French		
Spanish		

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

 Head of QA/QC Dept for Food Contact packaging materials and imported articles at Quality Management Dept. of Sklavenitis Group, Athens

Mar 2020 - Present

- Set specifications and legislative requirements for food contact packaging (flexible packaging, containers, single use and reusables)
- Managed the imports of FCM articles from EU and Non EU countries (Specifications, Compliance with legislation and EU standards)
- Collaborated with Greek and International Laboratories for monitoring safety in all FCM packaging and articles.
- 2nd party Audits in suppliers.
- Food Technologist at Quality Systems Dept of Sklavenitis Group,
 Athens

Feb 2018 - Mar 2020

- Developed specifications and labelling for PL FCM and food and feed products.
- Organized and run the annual chemical and microbiological testing plan for PL products and process the data.
- 2nd party Audits in suppliers
- Food Technologist at QA Dept for Retail Stores of Sklavenitis Group, Athens

Feb 2015 - Feb 2018

- Worked in the Development & Implementation of HACCP in the Retail Stores and Distribution Centers.
- Conducted internal audits in Retail Stores and Distribution Centers.
- Trained the personnel on Food safety and HACCP System.
- Food Technologist at QA/QC Dept of Production Units of Sklavenitis Group, Athens

Jan 2005 - Feb 2015

- Set up and run an in house food microbiology laboratory which led to the reduction of annual cost analyses and better food safety monitoring.
- Worked in the Development, Implementation and Monitoring of HACCP of the production units of the company (Packaging of coffee, dried nuts, herbs and legumes, Catering, Meat cutting and deli production, Ice-cream, bakery and confectionary).
- Set up specifications for raw materials (coffee,dried nuts, herbs, spices, cereals, meat, dried legumes)
- Collaborated with Marketing Department for labelling final prepacked products.
- Organized and run the annual chemical and microbiological testing plan for all products and processed the data.
- 2nd party audits in the suppliers of raw materials
- Managed customers' complaints.

HOBBIES

Traveling Swimming Reading

EDUCATION

MSc Applied Nutrition and Dietetics – Nutrition and Public Health at Harokopio University of Athens, Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Athens

Oct 2018 - April 2012

Relevant Coursework: Nutrition & Metabolism, Food quality and safety, Novel and functional food, Research methods and statistics, Food microbiology

Bachelor in Food Technology at Technological Institution of Athens, Department of Food Technology and Nutrition, Athens

Oct 1999 - Dec 2004

Relevant Coursework: Food microbiology, Food Chemistry, Biotechnology, Biochemistry, Food Processing and Engineering, Food Quality and Safety, Food packaging, Statistics, Food legislation.

CERTIFICATES

Plastics Conference (Athens)

2024, 2022, 2021

Food shelf life prediction methodology (Agricultural University of Thessaloniki)

2012

ISO 22000 (TUV Hellas)

2006

Development, Implementation and Audit of HACCP Certification (National Technical University of Athens)

2005

MEMBERSHIPS

Registered trainer for Food safety at Hellenic Food Safety Authority (EFET), Athens

2015